# **Bella Nicholson**

**♀** Amsterdam, Netherlands

bellanich.github.io

in bella-nicholson

O bellanich

American

Resourceful Machine Learning Engineer with 3+ years of experience in a diverse set of organizations, ranging from tech startups and scaleups to an establish tech company. A life-long learner with a passion for optimizing ML models for real-world applications on resource-constrained devices. Excited about the intersection between engineering and AI research.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Machine Learning Engineer

#### **Brenntag**

Mov 2023 - Present

Amsterdam, Netherlands

At the world's leading chemical distributor, I deployed and maintained ML products across 70+ countries. Thus far, I've:

- Migrated a virtual Al assistant (earning €30+ million in annual revenue) to a more cost-effective and secure AWS platform
- Developed a real-time **notification system** to monitor critical ML jobs and model metrics, **improving system visibility**
- Standardized quality controls across 15+ ML project components through the creation of a CLI package prototype

# **Artificial Intelligence Consultant**

#### **Deloitte Consulting**

m Sept 2021 - Oct 2023

Amsterdam, Netherlands

As a contracted ML engineer, I optimized and implemented ML solutions for diverse clients, delivering:

- Increased system robustness of a Dutch e-classified ads platform's "For You" page, introduced MLOps best practices
- Launched a self-paced, ML-focused coding training website to standardize and improve code quality across Deloitte NL
- Centralized large-scale model storage, experiment tracking across various environments for a German steel conglomerate

# Machine Learning Research Intern

#### Crunchr

∰ Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

Amsterdam, Netherlands

At a people analytics platform, I conducted graph-based representation learning research for the development of ML products:

- Built a proof of concept, one-off representation learning process to encode relational database entity information
- Demonstrated approach validity by applying deep neural networks to downstream classification tasks on process outputs

# **Computer Vision Intern**

#### Cubelizer

m June 2017 - July 2017

Madrid, Spain

As part of a Google-backed edge computer vision startup, I improved customer detection 12% in retail space optimization:

- Developed a video stream-based object detection method in compliance with EU privacy regulations
- Applied image processing and classical machine learning techniques to low-resolution images

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) Specialization

# DeepLearning.Al

Curriculum

₩ Sept 2022

Certificate

# **EDUCATION**

# Master of Science, Artificial Intelligence

# **University of Amsterdam**

🗎 Sept 2018 - Dec 2020

- ♠ Amsterdam, Netherlands
- Courses on AI, including Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, and Reinforcement Learning
- Thesis on "Interpretable Representation Learning for Relational Data" in collaboration with Crunchr
- Cum laude (8.0/10.0)

# Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering

# The College of New Jersey

🗎 Sept 2014 - May 2018

**♀** Ewing, New Jersey, USA

- Met national engineering standards by passing the Fundamentals of Engineering Other Disciplines Exam
- Magna cum laude (3.8/4.0)

# **PROJECTS**

#### Pocket Multi-Modal Large Language Model

- Deployed a custom embedded, vision-text foundation model across various iOS devices (laptop, phone, tablet)
- Extended an existing large language model hardwareoptimization framework to quantize a new multi-modal model
- Documented results and process in a 4-part blog post series

# **Python Machine Learning Template**

- Automated a comprehensive Python ML project setup process with a project template and 3 simple bash commands
- Enabled streamlined project creation with pre-built tests, an automated build process, and auto-generated documentation

# **SKILLS**

# Programming languages & tooling

Python, Git (2016-present), Bash (2018-present), Terraform (2023-present), SQL (2019-present), Docker (2022-present)

#### **MLOps** platforms

Amazon Web Services (2021-present), Google Cloud Platform (2022-present), Databricks (2022-present), Azure DevOps Platform (2021-2022)

#### ML frameworks

PyTorch (2018-present), PySpark (2022-present), FastAPI (2021-present), Tensorflow (2021-2022), Keras (2022)

### Languages









Spanish German

Russian